Let's make great prompts with the OCEAN process!
O is for Objective. Set a clear goal!
Whether you're explaining a topic or
writing a story, defining what you want helps
the model deliver exactly what you need.
For example, start with, 'I
want to explain what climate
change is.' This sets a basic
goal for the model to follow.
C is for Context. Give the model all the
background info: audience, style, key details.
You could expand the prompt to 'Explain what
climate change is, to middle school students,
in a friendly and simple way.' Which
helps set the appropriate style and tone.
E is for examples. Give the model examples
you like to guide the model's output.
For instance, you might provide links or describe
other educational videos that explain science
topics simply and engagingly, helping the
model understand the desired output style.
A is for Assess. Assess the output from the model.
Does it match your goal? Check for clarity,
relevance and any unfairness. For example,
ask 'Is this easy to understand?' and 'Does it
cover what I needed?' to ensure it's on point.
N is for Negotiate. If it's
not perfect - negotiate.
Improve the output by giving the model clear,
honest feedback to make the
output closer to what you want.
Once it's pretty close, the rest
is up to you... the human editor.
Finally, go through and edit the work yourself.
The model has done the heavy lifting,
but your final and unique touch
ensures quality and accuracy.
Any work you say is yours,
should actually be your work!